As Prophet T.B. Joshua was ministering prayer to the congregation at the Monday live prophetic service
in the name of Jesus Christ, a man cried out to him for his special attention.
I am a blasphemer.
Are you a pastor?
Yes, sir.
You are a blasphemer?
Yes, sir. I have a confession to make.
The confession is that we have been praying that God should take away your power.
We are PFN (Pentecostal Fellowship Nigeria) in Anambra State, Nigeria.
I came to meet you. I have never seen a pastor like you.
I have never seen your type.
Why were you people praying to take away my life?
We were seeing you as an anti-Christ.
And even that the Anointing Water was initiation into the marine world.
We said it was bewitching. The people were mesmerized; they'd just dance and fall
and that it was not real power from Heaven.
Why?
These are lies of the enemy. I have come here for forgiveness.
That's why I came so that it would be well with me.
So you are a pastor?
Yes, sir.
So, all the pastors in which state?
Anambra.
Yes, sir.
You people were praying that God should take away my life?
And humble you.
Okay, thank you. I want to see you, sir.
Go and wait for me.
Emmanuel!
(God with us - Matthew 1:23)
I am Pastor Chidi Daniel;
a pastor with Grace of God Mission in Anambra State, Nigeria.
I also belong to the PFN (Pentecostal Fellowship Nigeria).
Based on the information from our superiors, those I highly esteemed, I was ruined.
That was the position.
I was appointed as music and crusade director and as such, I went around
saying what they told me to say - that was a fallacy -
that the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, sleeps with snakes and lives in the water.
You can imagine...
And because of this, I went about telling people not to go to The SCOAN.
I said it was an anti-Christ church and "the synagogue of satan"
where nothing good can come out from.
Because I said these things, I didn't know I was ruining myself too.
The problems continued for me.
I didn't know where to turn to.
My children and family were ruined.
I lost my wife because of breast cancer, and my children died in an accident.
I got married to another woman but there was a problem. She left and went to her people.
The ministry was in shambles, and I didn't know what to do.
I asked myself, "What is wrong? I'm preaching the Gospel and it is a gateway to blessings.
Why is my case an exception?"
I was confused.
I went to visit one of my cousins who is a doctor, and I watched Emmanuel TV.
I saw miracles that looked incredible, and I wondered.
My cousin said that this was hypnosis, that they were being mesmerized
and that when they were dazed, they collapsed on the ground.
Then I saw the Anointing Water.
I saw healing, deliverance and all manner of miracles through the Anointing Water.
I said that this man was living in the water and that this was another dimension of initiating people too.
I refused to accept the miracles and the authenticity of the mercy of God to humanity.
I was always seeing the negative side and there were repercussions upon my life and ministry.
Other pastors who watched Emmanuel TV were always telling me
that the miracles were not real but stage-managed. You can't believe it.
Even on Monday after my confession, three pastors called me.
I know that these are people that have Emmanuel TV in their homes.
But they are like the 'old' pharisees who stand on the way,
not allowing people to enter into their miracles.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I have discovered that the appointment as a crusade director has amounted to disappointment
and has brought ruin. My body is sick. Nothing is working.
I asked another friend of mine who is a medical doctor.
He told me that I have a confession to make, that I used to speak evil against the man of God
and that the Bible says that sin against man can be forgiven
but sin against the Holy Spirit would never be forgiven.
I didn't have the courage to come to The SCOAN
after I had told people that nothing good can come out of this place.
It was a difficult situation for me.
I still went back to watch Emmanuel TV in another pastor's house.
Then I met another pastor who told me that I had wronged an authority in Christ.
I said, "I have never insulted any man of God. Who could it be that I have insulted?
T.B. Joshua of The SCOAN, do we call him a man of God?"
The pastor told me, "You have missed it. Are you the one who makes people men of God?
Prophet T.B. Joshua is the one who can deliver you. You must go to him for deliverance".
It wasn't easy for me to come; it was another mountain before me.
I had to summon up courage, and I came to The SCOAN.
I came on Monday.
The wise men came and attended to me. I thank God.
When finally the man in the Synagogue, the man anointed, the man of the now...
When Prophet T.B. Joshua appeared, he was very humble;
he didn't look like us who dressed to intimidate.
I saw what I had never seen among my fellow preachers and old founders who are bishops.
Prophet T.B. Joshua hugged me. He laughed. He took pictures with me. Oh, what a simplicity!
What a humility! What a compassion!
Somebody even asked him for his Bible and he gave it to him.
I said, "No, I have not seen this kind".
Something was saying within me, "If we can produce these types, there will be peace in Nigeria".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Since I came, I have seen it in another way;
I see the place as an institution in your life and your word.
No one can see you on the road and believe that you are a Holy Ghost machine!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I'm sorry, man of God. I have sinned against the Holy Ghost and the Anointed of God.
Please, have mercy on me.
He has been troubled for the past one week.
I think he has expressed his feelings.
My relationship with my Nigerian pastors, God is aware.
If my people had seen what is happening here clearly,
you people from other countries wouldn't have access to me.
Now God will begin to open that understanding.
You know, this is the church of all nations.
My country's position should not be more than half percent.
If they had seen and accepted me in the beginning, it would have disturbed my mission to the world.
It is the will of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If they had accepted me and seen me clearly, it would have disturbed my mission to the whole world.
This church would have become a Nigerian church and it is not only a Nigerian church.
God is aware.
What they have been doing from the beginning was never a sin - God is aware.
I repeat again. God decided to allow that to happen.
God can use any foolish thing.
He used that to keep me for the nations and the whole world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Just believe you are my father, you are my brother.
Your pain is my pain now.
Your trouble is my trouble, your pain is my pain.
Two believers are better than one.
Thank you very much. Hallelujah.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today,
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing Lives, Changing Nations, and Changing the World.
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 03/01/2019
CR Robert Begier 13/04/2019